Bilegjargal Jargalsaikhan "Jargal"

https://bilegjargal.github.io/portfolio

Email: bjargal56@gmail.com Mobile: +1-641-451-3892 http://linkedin.com/in/bilegjargal-jargalsaikhan

SUMMARY

Interested in Javascript technologies. Experienced in enterprise system development using ReactJS, NodeJS, and the Agile/SCRUM software development method. Have an understanding of functional and object-oriented programming. Problem solver and a team player. Willing to work on both front-end and back-end components.

SKILLS

- Frameworks: Node.is, ReactJS, Angular, ExpressJS, Agile/SCRUM, Jest
- Programming: Javascript(ES6), TypeScript, HTML, CSS, SASS, SQL, NOSQL, MongoDB
- Tools: Git, NPM, YARN, RESTful API, Ubuntu, Linux Mint

EXPERIENCE

Career Note: Completed on-campus studies and currently taking distance education courses to complete a Master's Degree in Computer Science(Available for full-time, W-2 employment)

ITZONE COMPANY

Ulaanbaatar, Mongolia, Software Developer, Sep 2016 - Jul 2018

- Working as a full-stack software developer on a business tool for contract management, using ReactJS Redux, Node.is, ExpressJS, and MongoDB, contributing to all phases of the software development process, including sprint planning, development, unit testing(JEST), iteration reviews, and deployment.
- Implemented a new function to add dynamic fields to a contract document. Resulted in a 30 percent reduction in the implementation time for new customer.
- Created a feature that generates a contract payment schedule by weekly, monthly or custom time interval with automatic invoice creation.
- Implemented CI/CD(continuous integration/continuous delivery) to my team using cucumber-Gherkin syntax. As a result our production delivery became more reliable and bug free.
- On-site client development to guickly solve many major and minor bugs. Awarded Customer Happiness Award in the first quarter of the year.

ITZONE COMPANY

Ulaanbaatar, Mongolia, Software Developer-Intern, Part-time, Sep 2015 - Sep 2016

- Contributed to the development of a Supply Chain Management System and Customer Relationship Management System as part of a full ERP system. Used Javascript(ES6), C#, and Oracle SQL technology
- Created a back-end logic to compute all types of transaction flows over the finance and inventory modules, resulting in a 20 percent improvemeent in inventory and finance department workflows while completely eradicating faulty transactions.

EDUCATION

 Maharishi University of Management Master of Science in Computer Science;

Fairfield, IOWA Aug. 2018 - In progress

 Mongolian University of Management Bachelor of Science in Computer Science;

Ulaanbaatar, Mongolia Aug. 2012 - Jun. 2016